(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-04T22:05:10.923803",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
For aeons, light and dark have fought ceaselessly,
for dominion over the world.
Whispers echo of a dark lord, whose insidious grip on the realm is marked by insatiable lust,
twisted jealousy, ravenous greed, unrelenting vanity, and possessive manipulation.
A group of adventurers rose to face this threat with hidden wishes of secrets and shadows untold.
First, there was Namu,
quick as an owl in the night, a thrill-seeking thief she was, who hunted in the fringes of society.
Next was Cora, a passionate chronomancer and hostess, whose connections to this world felt as thin as the threads of time she manipulated to build her harem.
Vailin was a guardian of nature whose sweet, charming exterior belied her true nature.
Descended from the heavens, Irisa brought tidings of doom, her innocent...
Clumsy demeanor stood in contrast to her
perfectionist tendencies.
Lastly, Hexa,
a bard who had yet to find her spotlight.
Dazzling were her performances,
whilst her silent dreams of recognition awed e'er her heart.
On a warm summer night, amidst the flickering candlelight of the Singing Shark,
in, they found their fates intertwined
with that of a malevolent dark lord, whose shadow slowly consumed everything in their path.
Hey Faelyn, how dost thou cope with death?
The fear thereof, I mean.
Tending to my plants helps stave off the looming specter of the void, if but for a spell.
Plants, huh?
Try them once.
Kill them all.
Yes, I'm destined to bring death one way or another.
Mayhaps thou art stick to nursing pines rather than plants, Hexa.
Nature's children are precious.
Thy liver is not.
I'll drink to that!
Comely maiden, might I follow thee home?
Twice my mother's wish that I follow my dreams.
A fine distraction, Kora.
Namu is so clever, isn't she?
Thou mistakest me for thine accomplice, Namu.
Canst thou not see I'm trying to work my magic here?
Already resorting to time magic to ensnare thy quarry?
Tush, pretty turn of phrase. I hardly need magic to court a maiden fair,
merely my unending charm.
Hast thou not enough trinkets already?
I take no more than I need to survive, I promise.
Would seem at least someone is getting lucky tonight.
Let me see. What'd you get?
Fie! Here comes the guard. That is my cue to vanish.
Namu, methinks the guard doth not arrive bathed in heavenly light.
Greetings, esteemed patrons.
I seek stout-hearted souls to accompany me on a dangerous...
How charming.
Tis is not a journey to be taken lightly.
The darkness grows stronger by the day.
Join me, and thy deepest wish will be granted.
Deepest wish?
Sounds like a ruse to me.
What think you?
Might be.
But what if it's not?
Oi, shiny lady!
Where's ol' I? So go on,
spin us your tale.
How can we trust thee?
Who art thou, anyway?
I understand your skepticism.
In times like these, we all have our doubts.
My name is IRyS. I descended from the celestial realm on a holy quest to end the dark lord's reign.
'Tis foretold that by vanquishing the dark lord, one's heart's desires will be granted.
What dost thou mean by our heart's desire?
Each of you carries within you a longing that drives you.
This quest can make those aspirations a reality.
Have you any proof?
There.
Now dost thou believe me?
Kora, what is wrong?
Thou lookest like thou hast seen a ghost.
What witch craft hast thou wrought upon her, foul enchantress?
I only showed her the truth.
Is this the future?
Oh, one moment. I shall return forthwith.
Indeed, it...
Where'd she go?
Ah, she sha'n't be gone long.
Watch, she'll turn anon.
Though it may beggar belief,
IRyS speaks the truth.
Our wishes can be granted.
Truly? We can wish for anything?
Any wish.
Any wish?
Well then,
wherefore do we tarry? Let us away!
(諦めない強さなら)
(If you have unyielding strength,)
(明日が見えないのなら)
(If you cannot see tomorrow,)
僕らは迷ってた 真っ暗狭い部屋
We were lost in a pitch-black, narrow room,
僕らはあがいてた 光差すほう
We were struggling toward the shining light.
不安やしがらみは 大きく膨らんで
Anxiety and entanglements swelled up large,
襲いかかる 逃げ場はない 差し伸べる手も
Closing in with nowhere to run, even the hands reached out—
嫌というほどに 繰り返して
Repeated to the point of disgust,
それでも まだまだ 与えるのか
Yet still, will you give us more?
試練の日々よ
Oh, days of trial!
諦めない強さなら それなりに平等だけど
If you have unyielding strength, it's fair in its own way, but
振り絞ったよ 今にもダメになりそう
I squeezed out all my strength, about to break any second.
そんなとき ふと見上げた 先駆者たちの言葉には 同じ香り 感じたんだ
At that moment, glancing up, in the words of those who came before, I felt the same scent.
僕らは夢を見た さまざま 思い思い
We dreamed various dreams, each as we pleased,
僕らは賭けてみた お互いに全て
We placed our bets on everything, mutually.
勝率や現実 ときには振り払って
Shaking off win rates and reality at times,
泣けばいい 悔めばいい 途中経過さ
It's fine to cry, fine to regret, it's just along the way.
夢中で息荒く 走り続け
Running on breathlessly in a dream,
気づけば無数の仲間たちに 支えられながら
Before I knew it, supported by countless comrades—
明日が見えないのなら その方角は間違いさ
If you cannot see tomorrow, that direction is mistaken.
一呼吸置いて ゼロからの近道もある
Take a breath; there's also a shortcut from zero.
簡単じゃないことでも 複雑に絡まる前に どうか一度 見せにおいで
Even if it's not easy, before it gets tangled up complexly, please, show it to us once.
出会ったんだ
We met,
魅かれたんだ
We were drawn in,
それが奇跡
That is a miracle.
君にありがとう
Thank you to you.
きっと思いや強さなら それなりに平等だけど
Surely, if you have unyielding strength, it's fair in its own way, but
振り絞ったよ 今にもダメになりそう
I squeezed out all my strength, about to break any second.
そんなとき ふと見上げた 先駆者たちの言葉には 頼らない 歌うよ
At that moment, glancing up, in the words of those who came before, not relying on them, I will sing!
明日が見えないのなら その方角は間違いさ
If you cannot see tomorrow, that direction is mistaken.
一呼吸置いて ゼロからの近道もある
Take a breath; there's also a shortcut from zero.
簡単じゃないことでも 複雑に絡まる前に どうか一度 見せにおいで
Even if it's not easy, before it gets tangled up complexly, please, show it to us once.
Quite the jig thou didst dance back at the tavern.
Was it to charm people or to scare away crows? I couldn't tell.
A brazen stone to cast when none would countenance you without your magic.
You're both very charming, but not as lovely as Namu.
Huh?
Lovely, you say?
Is the moon not beautiful tonight?
Uh...
Although we ought not linger,
rumor has it that an evil hag liveth in these parts,
and now whet her appetite, like the flesh of adventurers.
What art thou hiding, she thinks?
What dost thou not want us to know about these woods?
Tell us more about this hag.
Aye, a frightful yawn doth excite my spirit!
Canst thou all see she speaketh false?
Gumi and her friend Darla were adventurers who gathered fruit in these woods.
Gumi had heard of a trove of berries hidden deep in the forest, so they ventured in and found a grove untouched by man or beast.
They began picking the berries in pure bliss, that is, until they heard a loud, snapping and crunching sound.
What was that?
They looked around, but saw nothing. Spooked by the unnatural sound, they decided to leave, but twas too late. They lost track of time.
Night had fallen and darkness shrouded the woods. They split up and marked their path with berries.
After some time, Gumi heard a scream followed by a bone-chilling crunch.
Gumi ran down the berry trail with all the haste she could muster. The berries underfoot began to ooze a strange, red substance. It seeped into the ground.
Each stain bigger than the last. Breathless, she came upon a large puddle of red, and in the centre, a pile of teeth.
Frozen in horror, she looked up and beheld a grotesque hag looming over her,
Darla's hair hanging from her mouth. Before she could react, the hag lunged!
I'll mean to rob us of any chance of peaceful slumber?
Dost thou mean to rob us of any chance of peaceful slumber?
Merely trying to keep you all on your toes.
It's working. I don't think I'll sleep a wink tonight.
Let us abscond from this place, starting to feel like we're being watched.
None of you belong here.
An unwise choice. None of you belong here.
ようこそ 深い森の奥
Welcome to the depths of the forest
珍しい お客さんね
Such unusual guests
悪いけど ここから先では
Sorry, but from here on out
森でのマナーがあるの
There are rules to the forest
ぽー ぽー
Hoo, hoo
フクロウが知らせる
The owls announce
ぽー ぽー
Hoo, hoo
客が来たと
That a guest has arrived
ぽー ぽー
Hoo, hoo
フクロウが知らせる
The owls announce
何かが始まる予感
A premonition that something is beginning
ラウー ラウー 何が見たいの
Laau, laau, what do you want to see?
ラウー ラウー あなた次第
Laau, laau, it's up to you
悪いけど ここではあなたは
Sorry, but here you are
招かれざる客なの
Unwelcome guests
ぽー ぽー
Hoo, hoo
フクロウが知らせる
The owls announce
ぽー ぽー
Hoo, hoo
客が来たと
That a guest has arrived
ぽー ぽー
Hoo, hoo
フクロウが知らせる
The owls announce
何かが始まる予感
A premonition that something is beginning
ぽーぽー
Hoo-hoo
ラウー　ラウー　何が見たいの
Rau, Rau, what do you want to see?
ラウー　ラウー　あなた次第
Rau, Rau, it's up to you.
悪いけど　ここではあなたは　招かれざる客なの
Sorry, but here you are uninvited guests.
ぽーぽー
Hoo-hoo
フクロウが知らせる
The owl announces
ぽーぽー
Hoo-hoo
客が来たにと
That guests have arrived.
ぽーぽー
Hoo-hoo
フクロウが知らせる
The owl announces
何かが始まる予感
A premonition that something is beginning.
(La〜)
(La~)
ぽーぽー
Hoo-hoo
フクロウが知らせる
The owl announces
ぽーぽー
Hoo-hoo
客が来たにと
That guests have arrived.
ぽーぽー
Hoo-hoo
フクロウが知らせる
The owl announces
何かが始まる予感
A premonition that something is beginning.
The forest unburdens itself to me.
The trees seem to whisper of endless paths and treasures untold.
What secrets dost thou hide?
If I can keep us here longer, I might uncover these secrets.
Mayhaps with a little magic, a subtle persuasion, I could convince them.
It looks like we should be going this way, right?
Thou art mistaken, we can't go that way.
Therein lies the lair of a bear, most fierce. We must avoid it at all costs.
We can handle a bear.
This is the shortest path to remove us from this wood most expediently.
I know these woods well. Give me the map.
No.
Give it to me!
Thy tongue doth drip with deceit. Why should we trust thee to lead the way?
Perhaps I can lead us out.
The trees tell me of an easy and safe path.
But trees? Trees have no tongues, Faulen.
Why don't we just go...
that way?
Oh, but they do harken well.
Dai re giliath, li ar mi nuor, tarn lîn, can ednawg...
Faulen, what art thou?
Oh, the forest is so beautiful.
I see it now. Why are the trees so wiggly all of a sudden?
IRyS, avert thine eyes! The fireball is no friend!
Look at me, I'm dancing with the forest spirits!
Be careful, thou mayst turn into a tree!
Really?
Cool.
What's in here? More secrets? Back off! How dare thou least lay grubby hands on my belongings? Dost thou need to open a thrift shop with all this?
IRyS, tis a miss with the leaves. They're watching us.
They aren't watching us. Merely judging thee.
Take that, you pathetically infiltrated... Back, you fiends! The hag!
How's my cheese?
There's no hag.
The spell hath worked perfectly!
Look at the chaos I've created.
'Tis almost too easy.
Alas, I had no choice.
They wanted to leave so soon.
Why would they want to miss out on the magic this forest holds?
Do I manipulate them too much?
Nay, they will thank me for showing them the wonders of the forest.
The forest, however, is not nearly as magical as my beloved Namu.
She knows these woods so well.
I wonder why.
Every time she speaks, I can't help but be drawn to her.
I may have cast a spell on her, but 'tis she that had enchanted me.
Follow me.
檻の中 あたしの愛猫
In a cage, my beloved cat,
お帰りなさい 君にニャオ
Welcome back, meow to you.
悪い子ね 汚れたお身体で
You've been naughty, with a dirty body.
行きはよいで帰りは怖い
Easy to go, but scary to return,
愛を知らない飽き猫さん
A fickle cat who doesn't know love.
間抜けな愛嬌とかそりゃ結構
Your silly charm is quite something,
眺めっこ ほらバレバレで もう躁
Staring contest, it's obvious, you're manic.
なんで？お仕置きだ 自己嫌悪
Why? It's your punishment, self-loathing.
君はあたしだけの愛猫だよ？
You're my one and only love cat, you know?
ダンダン好キニナル 好キニナル ネエ 愛シテ
You will gradually grow to love me, hey, love me.
可愛いね 首輪つけてニャオ
You look cute with a collar, meow.
大切に愛でてあげるニャオ
I'll cherish and give you my love, meow.
檻の中の子猫ちゃん
Little kitten in the cage,
愛のダンスをさぁ踊りましょ
Let's dance the dance of love now.
喉鳴らし 擦り寄って ほらどうぞ？
Purring, snuggling up, there you go, how about that?
眺めっこ あら甘えん坊さんね
Staring contest, oh, you're such a spoiled one.
そっぽを向いてもそりゃ結構
Even if you turn away, that's fine.
君はあたしだけの愛猫なの
You're my one and only love cat.
ダンダン好キニナル 好キニナル ネエ 愛シテ
You will gradually grow to love me, hey, love me.
逃げられしないのおバカね
You can't run away, you silly thing.
無償の愛が欲しいの 愛して
I want unconditional love, love me.
餌が欲しいね だって君は愛猫さん
You want food, don't you? Because you're my beloved cat.
Finally, we're out of those godforsaken woods!
Where's my bag? I can't find it.
Thou must have mislaid it when we got lost.
Thou took it, just down notch! Don't play innocent!
H-i-i-s worthless baubles! To what end?!
I spied failing with the bag in the forest. She probably took it.
Surely thou thinks it's not that I would take something of thine, Namu?
Nay, thou art right.
But see, my knees replenish our funds again.
The bait must be missing my patronage right now. I shan't keep them waiting.
I shall see if I can make some coin performing at the local pub.
I need some peace and quiet.
Then, I suppose I shall buy some herbs.
Look at her, so perfect, so effortless. Why, heaven, can I not be this perfect? This beacon of grace doth mock my every stumble and fall.
What curse is it that I am condemned to live in this clumsy husk?
They laugh at my awkwardness, but I despise it with every fiber of my being. 'Tis a blight, a stain upon my soul.
My ambitions can never reach their full potential in this state.
How can I ever be taken seriously when I can't control my limbs?
I'm a mockery... a joke to be pitied and scorned.
Oh my god
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Spoiler for love: "Break up"-ish
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spoiler for life: "Death"-ish
なにそれ意味深で かっこいいじゃん…
What's that? So deep and cool...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだわ 失敬
Dancing with a wordbook like that, excuse me
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu tulu tu tu tulu "ish"
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
-ish, yeah? -ish, yeah?
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu tulu tu tu tulu "ish"
神っぽいな
God-ish
もういいぜ もういいぜ それ もういいぜ もういいぜ
That's enough, that's enough,
逆に興奮してきたなあ
on the contrary, I'm getting excited.
おっきいね おっきいね 夢 おっきいね おっきいね
It's big, it's big, your dream, it's big, it's big
景気いいけど 品性はTHE END
Economy's good, but quality's the end
うええい うええい
Yay, yay
“Gott ist tot”
"Gott ist tot"
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいな それ “My God”
That's god-ish, unfair, that's god-ish, "My God"
アイウォンチュウ ウォンチュウ IQが下がっていく感じ
I want you, want you, feels like my IQ's dropping
邪心っぽいな それ 畢竟 邪心っぽいな それ
That's wicked-hearted, after all, that's wicked-hearted
アイヘイチュウ ヘイチュウ 害虫はどっち
I hate you, hate you, which one of us is the pest?
その髪型 その目 その口元 その香水 その服 そのメイク
That hairstyle, those eyes, those lips, those clothes, that make-up
アレっぽいな それ 比況 アレっぽいな それ
They're that-ish, compare, they're that-ish
その名言 その意見 その批評 そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That witty remark, that opinion, that critique, that charisma, that gag, that sense
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 ぽいな ぽいな ぽい 憧れちゃう！
That's god-ish, unfair, "-ish", "-ish", "-ish", I adore it!
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu tulu tu tu tulu "ish"
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
-ish, yeah? -ish, yeah?
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu tulu tu tu tulu "ish"
神っぽいな
God-ish
メタ思考する本質は悪意？ 人を小馬鹿にしたような作意
Is the essence of meta-thinking malice? An artifice that looks down on others
無為に生き延びるのは難しい 権力に飲まれて揺らぐ灯り
It's hard to survive in idleness, the light wavers, swallowed by authority
神を否定し神に成り代わり 玉座で豹変する小物達 批判に見せかけ自戒の祈り
Denying god and taking the place of god, small fry changing on the throne, a prayer of self-discipline disguised as criticism
Do you know?
何言ってんの？ それ ウザい 何言ってんの？ それ
What 're you saying? That 's so annoying. What 're you saying?
意味がよくわかんないし 眠っちゃうよ マジ
I dunno what that means. I'm gonna fall asleep, seriously
飽きっぽいんだ オーケー みんな 飽きっぽいんだ オーケー
I'm easily bored, ok. Everyone's easily bored, ok
踊れるやつ ちょうだい ちょうだい ビーム
Gimme something I can dance with, gimme, beam
ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね 器 ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね
You're small, you're small, you're small-minded
天才ゆえ孤独ですね かっけぇ… かっけぇ…
Lonely because you're a genius. How cool... how cool...
“Gott ist tot”
"Gott ist tot"
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 神っぽいな それ “My God”
That's god-ish, unfair, that's god-ish, "My God"
超健康 健康 言い張って くだっていく感じ
It's like dropping dead while insisting, "I'm healthy, super healthy"
ヤケっぽいな それ 畢竟 ヤケっぽいな それ
That sounds desperate, in the end, that sounds desperate
もう哀愁 哀愁 エピゴーネンのヒール
How sorrowful, how sorrowful, epigone's heel
そのタイトル その絵 そのストーリー その音楽 その歌 そのメロディ
That title, that art, that story, that music, that song, that melody
アレっぽいな それ 比況 アレっぽいな それ
They're that-ish, compare, they're that-ish
その名言 その意見 その批評 そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That witty remark, that opinion, that critique, that charisma, that gag, that sense
神っぽいな それ 卑怯 ぽいな ぽいな ぽい 憧れちゃうわ
That's god-ish, unfair, "-ish", "-ish", "-ish", I adore it!
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu tulu tu tu tulu "ish"
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
-ish, yeah? -ish, yeah?
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる “風”
Tu tulu tu tu tulu "ish"
神っぽいな
God-ish
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Spoiler for love: "Break up"-ish
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Spoiler for life: "Death"-ish
すべて理解してはづらった 無邪気に踊っていたかった 人生
I understood everything and suffered, I'd just wanted to keep dancing innocently through life
Thy angelic humming speaks of a great darkness in you. Thou art sin-made to expel the demons within.
Demons? I have not any demons. But I thank thee for the compliment. Or thou nuen... I'm married to the chat, I'm afraid.
We're about to begin rehearsal. Take up that hymnal and join us. Why don't thee...
These beauties... Thou choir be.
Mayhaps I could give it a chance.
Come!
What songs are you singing?
Turn to page 165, and thou shalt see the lyrics there.
Uh...
Hi?
Hey, nice to meet you. Aren't you cute?
Huh? Uh... Hi.
Are you ready, everyone?
Let us begin.
Hey!
Uh... Hi?
Why don't we get out of here?
What dost thou say?
But, we haven't even started rehearsal yet!
What dost thou mean?
Hey!
Uh... Hi?
I fell in love the moment I laid eyes upon thee.
Have we met before?
Hey!
Uh... Hi?
Good day, I'm Kronii. What is thy name?
I'm Diana. Well met. Hast thou newly joined the choir?
Nay, but... I would much like if thou joined my w- I- I mean, I- I mean, l- life, life!
Thou art an amusing one. I should like to become better acquainted with thee.
Are you ready, everyone? Let us begin.
さあ、踊ろうか
Come, let us dance.
今日もまた美しい淑女が
It's another day, another beautiful lady
僕の元 訪れる
coming to visit me
微笑みを浮かべる貴女は 新しい妻となる
and you, smiling away, will become my new wife
禁断の悪魔との契約 手に入れた この力
A forbidden contract with the devil, this power I've obtained
僕を見た 全ての女は 魅了され 堕ちていく
All women who look at me are enchanted and fall
女性を魅了する力を手に入れた
I gained the power to charm women
男は一人住む屋敷の地下室に
A man in the basement of his mansion
気に入った女を次々と連れ込み
brought in women he liked one after another
ハーレムを作り上げた
and built a harem
毒を秘めたリビドーの味 突き刺した刃の快楽
The taste of libido harboring poison, the pleasure of a piercing blade
血と汗は混ざり合い やがて 紫の滴へと変わる
Blood and sweat mix together, soon turning into purple droplets
服を脱ぎ捨て抱き合えば 現実へはもう二度と戻れない
If we strip off our clothes and embrace, we can never return to reality
燃やされた昔の肖像画 捨て去った過去の僕
The burned portrait of the past, the past me I threw away
誰しもがあざけ笑った あの顔は忘れたい
Everyone sneered and laughed, I want to forget that face
傍らの可愛い娘を 抱き寄せてキスをする
Pulling the cute girl by my side close, I kiss her
彼女はそう かつて僕のこと 馬鹿にした幼馴染
She is the childhood friend who once made a fool of me
ある日を境にして国中の女が
One day, all the women in the country
いつしか次々と行方をくらませた
somehow vanished one after another
あるものは女房 あるものは娘を
Some lost their wives, some lost their daughters
失い途方に暮れた
and were left in utter despair
闇に染まるリビドーの色 とどまらぬ無限の情欲
The color of libido dyed in darkness, boundless and unstoppable lust
幻想は全てを呑み込み 僕はもう人ではなくなる
Illusion swallows everything, and I am no longer human
神に逆らい堕落する これが僕の望んでた狂気のnight
Rebelling against God and falling into depravity, this is the madness of the night I wished for
今日もまた美しい淑女が
Today, too, a beautiful lady
僕の元 訪れる
visits me.
さあおいで 僕の胸の中
Come into my chest,
踊ろうよ このハーレムで
let's dance in this harem.
近づいた 貴方を抱きしめ
Embracing you as you drew close,
微笑んだ その瞬間
the moment you smiled,
突然の 鋭い痛みと
with a sudden sharp pain,
血に染まる 僕の胸
my chest is dyed with blood.
消えた恋人を捜していた若者
A young man searching for his missing lover
居場所を突き止めた 悪魔の住む屋敷
pinpointed the mansion where the devil lives.
若者は女装して悪魔に近づいた
The young man dressed as a woman to approach the devil,
懐の刀を悪魔に突き刺した
and thrust the dagger in his bosom into the devil.
毒を秘めた刀がささり
The dagger containing poison pierced,
僕はその場に倒れこんだ
and I collapsed on the spot.
血と汗は混ざり合い やがて
Blood and sweat mix, and eventually
紫の滴へと変わっていく
turn into purple droplets.
術のとけた女たちは全て 我に帰り屋敷から逃げ出した
All the women whose spells were broken fled the mansion.
僕のこと 一瞬だけ見て
Looking at me for just a second,
最後に屋敷から出たのは
the last one to leave the mansion was
あの幼馴染 待ってよ
that childhood friend. Wait,
まだ君に好きだと言ってない
I haven't told you yet that I love you.
Well, how did I allow myself to be talked into this quest?
To suffer the odious hijinks of these bumbling fools.
A crude, unsightly, and boorish lot they are.
Me thinks they could scarce walk a straight line, much less perform — oh, God forbid — dance.
Me thinks they could scarce walk a straight line, much less perform—oh, God forbid—dance.
Their company doth abase me, who should be foremost among my peers.
Humble bard I may be, but the world shall soon know of my eminence and fawn and adore me as they should.
I may yet be unknown, but soon...
...once this silly quest is over and I have my wish, townsfolk will swoon over my ballads.
Royalty will beg me to grace their parties.
In the name of Hexa shall ring over Hill and Valley as the greatest performer this realm hath ever known.
And then... and then...
Say, is there anybody out there that wants to perform?
Is there none who dare take the stage? What, have you missed?
I see thee tap in thy feet to all the songs. Dost thou dance, dance?
Ah, me? Ah, I don't know.
Hey, please give us a song, miss! And we'll make us the thing I sing.
Well, thou art dressed like a singer. So a singer's god doth a singer make.
Very well. I'll do it.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. Are you ready for the greatest performance of your lives?
Once in a faraway, faraway world was a collar that coiled like a snake
I want someone please - I need someone please Oh, I listened close as it howled in ache
I want someone please—I need someone please. Oh, I listened close as it howled in ache.
Please don't be angry and please don't abandon me. Don't leave me here on my own (kay?)
It wrapped itself tightly, daily and nightly - only with praise would it loosen it's hold
It wrapped itself tightly, daily and nightly—only with praise would it loosen its hold.
I placed in the top of my class~
there's no one left for me to surpass
Don't I look cute in this dress?
I really, really must confess - it's tightening 'round my neck!
I really, really must confess—it's tightening 'round my neck!
Give me your love, all of your love, give me your love - all you can conjur up
Give me your love, all of your love, give me your love—all you can conjure up.
Give me your love, all of your love, till you go mad with ecstasy
All of the hurt, all of the ache - help me escape! Take it, oh take it away!!!
All of the hurt, all of the ache—help me escape! Take it, oh take it away!!!
All of the hurt, all of the ache -
help me escape! Take it, oh take it away!
Is there no end to this pain?
Grow as you may, but the necklace will stay just as small as the day it was found
It's so suffocating, the endless placating - no one is, no one is ever enough!
Won't lose to anyone, always ranked number one, aren't I a beautiful child? (Hey)
I'm better than her - I'm better than him, oh everyone, come round and gawk at perfection!
Meeting you right after school,
I'm finally confessing to you -
Ain't it too good to be true?
A girl, like me, in love with you - who's miserable, vulgar, and crude!
Give me your love, all of your love, give me your love - You can have everything
if I have you, I can have you - shoulder my load, now yours to behold
Still not enough, you're not enough - never enough.
Still I won't loosen my hold
Truly, I'm so sorry.
Give me your love, all of your love, give me your love - all you can conjure up
Give me your love, all of your love, till you go mad with ecstasy
I know it hurts - (it) only gets worse - God how it hurts - Soon you'll be craving the pain
This is my happiness now!
I know not how thou fared, but I was successful in my adventure.
More trinkets for thy thrift shop?
Nay, 'twas coin we needed. I merely took out a small loan from the bank. They shan't mind.
I acquired some healing potions. Luckily, 'twas a simple matter to trade for some of these jewels I found in the woods.
Thou liar!
'Twas thou who took my bag!
Thou misapprehendest this from me; I merely found these lying on the floor of the forest.
Mayhaps there was a bag? Confess about stealing my stuff!
Does every bag that happens to fall in the wood belong to thee? I reason is always acting selfishly. She's the newest, so 'twas probably her.
Thou darest to accuse me?!
If thou were truly innocent, would the thief not more likely be Hexa? She is simple and craven, and acted half-mad back there in the forest.
Me? Why art thou accusing me?
It could be none but Failing with her strange obsession with Namu.
Thy words ring true.
Can I just have the bag thou foundst in the forest?
Nay, 'tis mine!
I knew it was folly to undertake this quest with you all. Fie on you! Fie on you all!
Myself, all on thee! Thou wentest on a witless womanizer!
I saw thy pathetic attempts at charming innocent choir girls! Better to apply thy sorcery upon thyself, that thou might vanish to the betterment of the world.
Me? My romantic diversions deserve no concern to thee! Thou uncouth, my cake-faced rat!
Trust to thou and be my companions of flesh, with thine erratic figments and dreams.
Have ye all forgotten about our quest?
Why aren't thou in such a rush to go?
Why art thou in such a rush to go?
Dost thou steal it? Certainly not.
Only want us to continue our quest and not linger on this useless bickering.
I only want us to continue our quest and not linger on this useless bickering.
You two have been fighting or sticking to each other this whole time.
Make up your mind already. Do you like each other?
We like each other. Do we not, Nanomu?
If twas thou who stole my bag, then no, I don't like thee.
Really?
Look what thou hast done! Thou strucken her with a! Thou hast wounded her!
Look what thou hast done! Thou hast strucken her! Thou hast wounded her!
時の揺りかごで
In the cradle of time,
冷たい夢を見る
I dream a cold dream.
君が歌ってくれた
The lullaby you softly sang
優しい 優しい 子守唄
So gentle, so gentle...
君が望んだのは? 終わらぬ世界
What was it you wished for? An unending world.
俺が望むのは 世界の終わり...?
What I wish for... the end of the world...?
選ばれし声は 迷い、憂い 笑顔、労り
The chosen voice is lost in sorrow,
歌う 悲しみを 苦しみを
Singing, turning sorrow and suffering
喜びにと 笑顔に変えて
Into joy and smiles...
報われずに 君は朽ちていくのか? ただ、祈る 守りたい、この世界
Will you rot away unrewarded? I only pray, wanting to protect this world.
想いは 交わらない
Our feelings will never cross.
命を この手で全て、終わらせたい 巡る世界に やすらぎと祝福を
I want to end all life with my own hands—granting peace and blessing to this revolving world—
ああ 届かない 伝わらないよ 願いは虚しさだけを残して
Ah, it won't reach, it won't get through. My wish leaves behind only emptiness.
始まる 何故? 全て奪われ 未来を照らして
It begins. Why? Everything is taken. Illuminate the future—
痛み、苦しみ、背負わざれても... 永遠に続くレクイエム 抗えない運命を
Even if forced to bear pain and suffering... an eternal requiem. Against an inescapable destiny—
光を、運命を、全て今、解き放つ 闇を 解き放つ
Release the light, release fate now, release the darkness—
君が望んだのは? あなたの未来
What was it you wished for? Your future.
俺が望んだのは...何故? 戻らぬあの日...?
What I wished for... Why? That day that won't return...?
追い続けたのは 優しい笑顔 それだけなのに
All I kept chasing was that gentle smile, yet even so...
絶望を、希望に変えて 終わらない歌声を 叫び続けて 滅びの運命なら ただ、祈る
Turn despair into hope, an unending song. Keep screaming; if destruction is our fate, I only pray—
せめて今、弔いの 果てしくなく 遠く遠く
At least now, a mourning prayer, endlessly, far away...
歌よ 響け
Song, resonate!
巡り 巡る 世界に やすらぎと 祝福を 光を、運命を、闇を、解き放て
Grant peace and blessing to the revolving world. Release the light, fate, and darkness!
終わらない 絶望を 歌声を、希望に変えて 叫び続けて ただ祈る 君は朽ちていくの?
Turn endless despair and song into hope. Keep screaming, just praying. Will you rot away?
せめて今、弔いの 果てしくなく、遠く 遠く
At least now, a mourning prayer, endlessly, far away...
歌よ 響け
Song, resonate!
君が望んだのは... 俺が望んだのは...
What you wished for... What I wished for...
残された 声は 嘆き 君を想いながら
The voice left behind is a sigh, thinking of you.
独り、君のために歌う 独り、君のために歌う
Alone, I sing for you. Alone, I sing for you.
命を この手で全て、眠らせたら 巡る世界に やすらぎと祝福を
If I put all life to sleep with my own hands—granting peace and blessing to this revolving world—
ああ、朽ちていく 運命は終わり この身は 君となら どこまで でも...
Ah, rotting away, fate comes to an end. This body, if with you, will go anywhere...
始まる声 全て 叶えて 未来を照らして 滅び、散り行く この身とともに 永遠に続くレクイエム
Grant every starting voice, illuminate the future. Along with this body perishing and scattering, an eternal requiem.
抗えない運命を 光を、運命を、全て今、解き放ち 闇を 解き放ち
Against an inescapable destiny, release the light, release fate now, release the darkness—
光の 底に、 眠れ
Sleep at the bottom of the light.
Where is the Dark Lord?
Dark Lord, reveal thyself! We are here to defeat...
3, 2, 1
How queer.
The silence, it's...
Says who? This room was empty.
From the very beginning.
Why'd it be?
The quest began at the cusp of dawn
Blank map in hand eager to be drawn
Cascading secrets
Holding onto wishes untold
With every stride, a new tale bound to unfold
In realms never seen
In planes beyond belief
Smiles beamed and gleamed radiantly
Wonders hidden with each turn
Always together
In harmony, all perils can be weathered
A melody chases the laughter of five
Through days like forests deep and wide
When paths diverge
We meet again where dreams converge
Hear our hearts collide
Fears out of sight
Stars ever bright
Our promise ignites
Hours slip by with familiar song
Twilight's glow, the shadow's gone
Exchanging secrets
Knowing the power they behold
With every change, an old tale passed to be told
In trails never walked
In lands beyond one's thought
Lessons taught in destinies sought
Echoes of the world unknown
Searching for treasures
In harmony, our souls steadily tremor
A melody chases the laughter of five
Through nights like sand burying time
When paths diverge
We meet here where our dreams surge
Hear our hearts collide
Fears out of sight
Stars ever bright
Our promise ignites